Guide to the Charters and Certificates of Affiliation Collection GRAPHICS.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Charters and Certificates of Affiliation Collection
1888-1986
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
GRAPHICS.003
3 Linear Feet in 2 oversize boxes and 1 flat-file folder
The Charters and Certificates of Affiliation Collection is an artificial collection, collected and assembled by the Tamiment Library over the course of several decades. It consists of charters and certificates from a number of trade unions and organizations, several of which have manuscript collections at the Tamiment Library. The material in the collection ranges in date from 1888 through 1986, with the bulk of material falling between the 1920s and the 1960s.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library, New York University, a special collection documenting the history of United States radicalism, labor, and progressive social action, accumulated this artificial collection of charters and certificates gradually over the years.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in repository; provenance is unknown. Materials were likely separated from manuscript collections at the Tamiment Library. The following accession numbers are associated with this collection: 1950.255, NPA.1995.010, NPA.2000.033, NPA.2003.076, NPA.2005.248, NPA.2006.065, NPA.2006.069, NPA.2006.071, NPA.2008.003 and NPA.2009.003.
Arrangement
The Collection is arranged into two Series divided based on size. Items are arranged alphabetically.
Missing Title
Series I: Boxed, 1888-1986
Series II: Flat Files, 1921-1929
Scope and Content Note
The Charters and Certificates of Affiliation Collection consists of charters and certificates of affiliation from trade unions and organizations, several of which have related manuscript collections at the Tamiment Library. The material in the collection ranges in date from 1888 with a charter from the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America up to 1986 with a charter from the Communications Workers of America: Local 1153.
Related Archival Material
Associated Actors and Artistes of America Records (WAG 110)
Commercial Telegraphers Union Records (WAG 266)
Communications Workers of America, Local 1153 Records (WAG 132)
National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians (NABET-CWA) Records (WAG 197)
Young People's Socialist League Records (TAM 309)
Trade unions |z United States.; Certificates.; Charters.; AFSCME; United Hebrew Trades; Young People's Socialist League; National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians; United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America; Communications Workers of America. Local 1153 (Valhalla, N.Y.); Hebrew Actors Union.; National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians. Local 15 (New York, N.Y.); Screen Actors Guild; American Guild of Variety Artists; Associated Actors and Artistes of America
- Series I: Boxed, 1888-1986
  - Abraham and Strauss Department Store Employees' Union, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Amalgamated Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen of North America: Certificate of Affiliation, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees: Charter, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Guild of Variety Artists: Charter (copy), 1939 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Asociacion Puertorriqueno de Artistas y Technicos del Espectaculo: Charter (copy), 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers of America: Charter, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Communications Workers of America: Local 1153: Local Charter, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Communications Workers of America: Local 1153: Local Charter, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - German White Rats Actors Union: Charter, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hebrew Actors' Union: Charter (copy), 1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians: Certificate of Affiliation (copy), 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians: Charter, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Association of Broadcast Employees and Technicians: Local 15: Charter, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - National Council, Distributive Workers of America, Alliance for Labor Action, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Negro American Labor Council, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - New York City Central Labor Council: Certificate of Affiliation, circa 1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - New York State Industrial Union Council: Certificate of Affiliation, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - New York State Industrial Union Council: Charter, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Retail Grocery Clerks of Essex, Hudson, Union, Bergen, and Passaic Counties of New Jersey: Local 1245: Charter, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Screen Actors Guild: Charter (copy), 1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - State, County and Municipal Workers of America: Charter, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Telegraph Workers Federal Labor Union No. 22679: Charter, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners of America: Charter, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - United Hebrew Trades of the State of New York: Charter (2 items), undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Young People's Socialist League: Charter, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Young People's Socialist League: Charter, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Thomas E. Dewey certificate re Senate Bill Intro. No. 578, 1944 (Box Shared Tamiment 017, Folder 14)
- Series II: Flat-Files, 1921-1929
  - Associated Actors and Artistes of America: Charter (blank), undated (Flat-file 1, Drawer 1)
  - Commercial Telegraphers Union of North America: Certificate of Affiliation, 1929 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 1)
  - German Actors Association: Charter, 1929 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 1)
  - German White Rats Actors Union: (?) Branch: Charter, 1921 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 1)
  - New York City Central Labor Council: Charter, 1959 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 1)